

UI/UX Designer
Nairobi, Kenya
kelvinnjuguna99@gmail.com
+254704549859

PROFILE

Creative and experienced UI/UX Designer with a demonstrated history of working in the information technology and software development industry. Skilled in Mobile and Web Application Design, HTML, CSS, jQuery, JavaScript, English, Adobe XD, Adobe Illustrator, and Adobe Photoshop. Strong artistic and design enthusiast with a Bachelor's Science degree in computer technology-focused in Information Technology from Meru University of Science and Technology (MUST).

Having worked in teams, I have experience with best practices in coming up with UI/Ux designs, presenting the designs to teams and clients, coding and software design life cycles, agile methodologies, and writing test cases. Been using git for version control of my code and Behance as both my portfolio for designs done and for case studies on products and projects.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Head of design, Nouveta LTD, Nairobi

FEBRUARY 2021 - PRESENT

- Oversaw all aspects of design and development, and offered design solutions when necessary.
- Utilized crucial design software skills to assist with projects.
- Worked as a productive and positive team member to design, code, test, report, and debug operations.
- designing and prototyping user interfaces
- Gathering user requirements and carrying out research on new projects as well as new features
- Assigning and supervising of tasks within the design team
- Worked to ensure a positive and hassle-free customer experience.

Graphic and web designer, Nouveta LTD, Nairobi

APRIL 2019 - JANUARY 2021

- Planned, developed, tested, deployed, and maintained web applications.
- Delivered visually compelling animations and graphic elements.
- Designing of product logos, icons, illustrations, and other graphical elements for our software products.
- Prototyping and designing of both App and web applications.
- Developing HTML templates for dashboards and Web portals

During my time in this role, I managed to design a variety of both mobile and web applications efficiently and within strict timelines. My designs were positively received and appreciated. As a result, I was promoted to be the head of designs. Besides the designs being liked, I was always a team player as I worked closely with the front-end developers in writing code for these applications that even greatly helped reduce the time taken during development.

Graphic and web designer, Royal Cornerstone Capacity Building, Nakuru

AUGUST 2018 - MARCH 2019

- Helped to achieve a consistent look and visual theme across the website by promoting uniform fonts, formatting, images, and layout.
- Created and executed graphics in After Effects and Illustrator.
- Continually worked to enhance personal skills.

EDUCATION	
Computer Technology, Meru University of Science and Technology, Meru SEPTEMBER 2013 — DECEMBER 2017	
Graduated with second class upper division honors	
KCSE, Kegonge Boys Highschool, Embu	
Pursued my high school studies and attained an overall B+ grade	
LINKS	
Portfolio LinkedIn Inatagram Github	
SKILLS	
Adobe XD	Adobe Photoshop
CSS	Adobe Illustrator
HTML	JavaScript
Adobe After Effects	vue
Microsoft Office	
INTERNSHIPS	
IT Support and maintenance, Postal Corporation of Kenya (PCK), Nakuru	
IT Support and maintenance, Kenya Medical Training College (KMTC), Nakuru JUNE 2015 — AUGUST 2015	
REFERENCES	
Alex Wanjala Wafula from nouveta LTD alex@nouveta.tech +254 719 401837	
Dr. Mary Mwadulo from Meru University of Science and technology mwadulom@gmail.com +254 724 789102	
Andrew Mwangi from Nouveta LTD mwangi@nouveta.tech +254 728 592629	
LANGUAGES	

Swahili

HOBBIES

English

Swimming, drawing, painting, watching animations, and watching football